Keep your enemies close.
Black Mass is a drama, crime, history film directed by Scott Cooper.
The true story of Whitey Bulger, the brother of a state senator and the most infamous violent criminal in the
history of South Boston, who became an FBI informant to take down a Mafia family invading his turf.
James 'Whitey' Bulger, played by Johnny Depp.
John Connolly, played by Joel Edgerton.
Marianne Connolly, played by Julianne Nicholson.
Lindsey Cyr, played by Dakota Johnson.
FBI Agent Charles McGuire, played by Kevin Bacon.
Billy Bulger, played by Benedict Cumberbatch.
Black Mass is a 2015 American biographical crime drama
film about American mobster Whitey Bulger.
Directed by Scott Cooper and written by Mark Mallouk and Jez Butterworth, it is based on Dick Lehr and Gerard
O'Neill's 2000 book Black Mass: The True Story of an Unholy Alliance Between the FBI and the Irish Mob.
The film features an ensemble cast led by Johnny Depp as Bulger, alongside Joel Edgerton, Benedict
Cumberbatch, Kevin Bacon, Jesse Plemons, Peter Sarsgaard, Dakota Johnson, and Corey Stoll.
Principal photography of the film took place in
Boston between May and August 2014.
The film had its world premiere at the 72nd Venice International
Film Festival and was released by Warner Bros.
worldwide on September 18, 2015.
It received generally positive reviews and grossed
$100 million on a $53 million budget.
The film explores themes of prostitute, corruption,
boston, massachusetts, gangster, fbi.
The tone is dark and emotional.